Fury is born.
Furiosa: A Mad Max Saga is a action, science fiction,
adventure film directed by George Miller.
As the world falls, young Furiosa is snatched from the Green Place of Many Mothers
into the hands of a great biker horde led by the warlord Dementus.
Sweeping through the wasteland, they encounter the
citadel presided over by Immortan Joe.
The two tyrants wage war for dominance, and Furiosa must survive many
trials as she puts together the means to find her way home.
Furiosa, played by Anya Taylor-Joy.
Dementus, played by Chris Hemsworth.
Praetorian Jack, played by Tom Burke.
Young Furiosa, played by Alyla Browne.
The History Man, played by George Shevtsov.
Immortan Joe / Rizzdale Pell, played by Lachy Hulme.
Furiosa: A Mad Max Saga is a 2024 post-apocalyptic action film directed and
produced by George Miller, who wrote the screenplay with Nico Lathouris.
It is the fifth installment in the Mad Max franchise, and the first not focused on Max Rockatansky,
instead a spinoff prequel to Mad Max: Fury Road (2015) and an origin story for Furiosa.
Starring Anya Taylor-Joy and Alyla Browne as said character and set years before Fury Road, the film follows her life for over a
decade, from her kidnapping by the forces of warlord Dementus (Chris Hemsworth) to her ascension to the rank of Imperator.
Tom Burke also stars as Praetorian Jack, a military
commander who befriends Furiosa.
Several Fury Road cast members return in supporting roles, including John
Howard, Nathan Jones, and Angus Sampson reprising their characters.
The film begins in what can be seen as a green paradise of a solarpunk future and quickly
moves to the more traditional dieselpunk, which this franchise is known for.
Miller initially intended to shoot Furiosa back-to-back with Fury Road, but the former spent
several years in development hell amidst salary disputes with Warner Bros.
Pictures, Fury Road's distributor.
Several crew members from Fury Road returned for Furiosa, including Lathouris, producer Doug Mitchell,
composer Tom Holkenborg, costume designer Jenny Beavan, and editor Margaret Sixel (Miller's wife).
Filming took place in Australia from June to October 2022.
Furiosa: A Mad Max Saga premiered at the 77th
Cannes Film Festival on 15 May 2024.
It was released theatrically in Australia on 23 May 2024
and in the United States the following day.
The film received highly positive reviews from
critics and multiple award nominations.
It was named one of the Top Ten Films of 2024 by the National Board of Review, but was a
box-office bomb, grossing $174.4 million against its budget of $168 million.
The film explores themes of chase, post-apocalyptic
future, warlord, prequel, wasteland.
The tone is thought_provoking.